<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Think Different</title>
    <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/categories/finance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Think Different</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Savings Account in Malaysia</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/savings-account-malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 21:17:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/savings-account-malaysia/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Malaysians, at the very least, own one savings account. According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://databank.worldbank.org/data/Population-With-Acc-in-Fin-Institution/id/2a961711&#34;&gt;World Bank&lt;/a&gt;, 80.7% of Malaysians of the age 15 and above, have accounts in Financial Institution in year 2014. When compared to year 2011, it was only at 66.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an individual basis, one may have the following accounts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Savings Account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Deposit Account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investment Account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the focus would be in Savings Account, the complication comes when one is being bombarded by so many types of it. From Regular Savings Account to Basic Savings Accounts and other Youth Savings Accounts, Elderly Savings Accounts or even Branded Savings Accounts, it is no surprise that one would be confused with such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the big question is, &lt;em&gt;which savings account one should opt for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer, &lt;strong&gt;it depends.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few factors that would affect one&amp;rsquo;s decision in deciding which type of Savings Account to opt for; they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desired Interest Rate level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency of ATM withdrawals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency of Over-The-Counter (OTC) Transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequency of Interbank Giro (IBG) Transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for passbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other miscellaneous commercial requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-savings-account&#34;&gt;Types of Savings Account&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how many savings accounts, marketed by banks in Malaysia, they can be summed up to two main types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bankinginfo.com.my/Banking%20Info%20-%20Savings%20Account.html&#34;&gt;Regular Savings Account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bankinginfo.com.my/Banking%20Info%20-%20Basic%20Banking%20Services.html&#34;&gt;Basic Savings Account&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to have a better understanding, lets have a quick run-through on what &lt;strong&gt;Regular Savings Account&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Basic Savings Account&lt;/strong&gt; are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/0lZeg7r.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Account Opening&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;regular-savings-account&#34;&gt;Regular Savings Account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are a lot of &lt;em&gt;branded&lt;/em&gt; savings account offered by the local banks, the plain vanilla one, i.e. the regular savings account is pretty standard. Its typical characteristics are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No limit to withdrawal frequency in any ATM related to the local bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passbook: Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annual maintenance fee / Card fee: MYR 8 per annum, indicatively for ATM cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some that place deposits with the bank, giving them moolah while they can use it to earn more money (Current OPR as of published date is 3.00% and typical weighted avg of interest paid to regular savings account is 0.10%. Hence, bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is 2.90% per annum, free money) and charging that extra fee there, may not make sense. With that, the other alternative comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-savings-account&#34;&gt;Basic Savings Account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 1-Feb-2005, Bank Negara mandated all deposit-taking banks in Malaysia to offer such facility to all Malaysia citizens and Permanent Residents, as per this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bnm.gov.my/index.php?ch=en_press&amp;amp;pg=en_press&amp;amp;ac=950&amp;amp;lang=en&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Its objective, is to provide public with commonly used banking facilities to meet their general requirements, at minimal cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical characteristics for a Basic Savings Account are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OTC Transactions: Limited to 6 times per month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATM Withdrawals: Limited to 8 times per month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IBG Transactions: Limited to 2 times per month at MYR 0.53 (inclusive GST), subsequently, the bank has the right to charge higher amount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passbook: None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATM Card: Yes, provided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annual maintenance fee / Card fee: None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, which account is appropriate for one? The correct question to ask would be, which savings account would benefit one, based on one&amp;rsquo;s lifestyle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than experiencing overload in information, one would have to structure them so that the decision made, would be an informed one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay smart!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold Rush</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/gold-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/gold-rush/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-introduction&#34;&gt;An Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gold rush has always been in existent since the early 19th century. During those times, its definition leaned towards a period of feverish migration of workers to an area that has had a dramatic discovery of gold deposits. Since then, things have changed. Our society is gaining awareness that the value of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fiat_money&#34;&gt;fiat money&lt;/a&gt; depreciates over time and they have been on the bandwagon to search for investment vehicles with high yield, many of which perceived gold as one of the suitable investment vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this modern era, gold rush has taken into a new look. People are now buying physical gold (in the form of bullion or jewellery) or even paper gold (in the form of Exchange Traded Fund that trades in gold) in order to hedge inflation risk and depreciating value of fiat money. The complication arises when it comes to evaluating and considering the need for &lt;strong&gt;sustainable&lt;/strong&gt; investment vehicle which one definitely feels that he or she is not gambling his or her hard-earned money on some odds which is uncontrollable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://demonocracy.info/infographics/world/gold/images/demonocracy-gold-400-oz.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;400 Troy Oz of Gold 999.9 Fine Bullion Bar by Demonocracy.info&#34; title=&#34;400 Troy Oz of Gold 999.9 Fine Bullion Bar by Demonocracy.info&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gold-rush-really&#34;&gt;Gold Rush, Really?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtly, there are many people who have made their wealth via investing in gold and realizing a profit (note that I have included a caveat, realizing profit). One does not make money and only enjoy unrealized gain unless one realizes it via selling the asset. Over the period of 5yrs, gold prices has increased above 50% from (2008 until 2013) as below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infomine.com/investment/metal-prices/gold/5-year/&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://charts.infomine.com?288&#34; alt=&#34;5 Year Gold Prices - Gold Price Chart&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the assumption that fiat money will decrease in value and inflation continuously increase, does buying gold effectively hedge those risks in a sustainable manner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets delve deeper into some of usage of gold which could possibly contribute to its demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the main applications of gold are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jewellery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dental&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aerospace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gilding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gold.org/&#34;&gt;World Gold Council&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; data for gold demand for the year 2012, below are some interesting figures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45.5% accounts for jewellery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;34.3% accounts for investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.1% accounts for technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.2% accounts for central bank and other institution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Refer to this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gold.org/supply-and-demand/interactive-gold-market-charting&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; for more info)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the math above, one can ask a simple question, &amp;ldquo;Looking at the two largest chunks, jewellery and investment, does both of them really help to stimulate the economy and provide sustainable investment?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Charlie Munger shared, &amp;ldquo;Remember that highest and best use is always measured by the next best use&amp;rdquo;, thus, would be fair to compare with other investment vehicle. Lets take property investment, population has always been on the increasing trend (refer to chart below from World Bank).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://data.worldbank.org/share/widget?end=2015&amp;indicators=SP.POP.TOTL&amp;start=1960&amp;view=chart&#34; width=&#39;500&#39; height=&#39;333&#39; frameBorder=&#39;0&#39; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, it makes sense to invest in property be it for rental income or capital gain (lets hope there would not be another subprime mortgage crisis in the making).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Central Banks have been proven to use gold as their reserves, but to the fundamental economy, gold&amp;rsquo;s contribution is at a minimal. At the end, people tend to purchase gold because they perceive its value will continue to grow due to continuous demand from the Central Banks and also devaluation of fiat money; neglecting its economical fundamental contribution. This is almost akin to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tulip_mania&#34;&gt;tulipmania&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tulipmania-a-classic-example-of-non-fundamental-economical-contribution&#34;&gt;Tulipmania, A Classic Example of Non-Fundamental Economical Contribution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early 16th century, tulips were first grown in Western Europe. Not long later, the wealthy people in Amsterdam sought the bulbs, paid high prices for them. That is the onset of the world&amp;rsquo;s earliest financial crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the height of the tulip&amp;rsquo;s reputation, it became a must-have for all wealthy people. If they do not own them, they were considered to have bad taste. Not to mention, even the middle class people were caught in the frenzy, willing to spend preposterous price (for some, that involves half of his/her life savings) for a single bulb so that his/her friends will admire it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to have a feel on how crazy it was, the table below describes the price of a single Viceroy bulb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Value (florins)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two lasts of wheat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;440&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Four lasts of rye&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;558&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Four fat oxen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;480&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eight fat swine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;240&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Twelve fat sheep&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two hogsheads of wine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Four casks of beer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two tons of butter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;192&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A complete bed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A suit of clothes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A silver drinking cup&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2,500&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tulips were even traded on Amsterdam&amp;rsquo;s Stock Exchange and in other towns as well during the height of the tulipmania. Stockbrokers were cashing money into their pocket by creating fluctuation in the price of tulips and with such high demand, minor price flunctuation could translate to high volume of sales and purchases. Many individuals suddenly grew rich with this mania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were purchasing bulbs at a high price and intend to re-sell them for a profit. Such scheme could not last unless there are proper fundamentally backed economic value behind it. Someone had to pay such high prices and take possession of the bulbs. At the dawn of its crash, tulip traders could no longer find new buyers willing to pay inflated prices for their bulbs. With this realization, demand for tulips collapsed and prices dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people lost their savings and their homes due to their desire to join in the frenzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to read more on tulipmania &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thetulipomania.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is always very important to do some number crunching along with rationalization on what investment vehicles to opt for. Always opt for the one which has proper economical fundamentals (such as stocks or property investments) which are backed by fundamental figures. At the end, we are the stewards of our own money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Value Investing</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/principles-of-value-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/principles-of-value-investing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Intelligent-Investor-Definitive-Investing-Practical/dp/0060555661&#34;&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/a&gt; is definitely one of the best book for all value investors out there. It combines business philosophy, rationalization and mathematics to argue on the latent potential of value investing by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benjamin_Graham&#34;&gt;Benjamin Graham&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-n6rqj9PXCaI/URC2e8x5mVI/AAAAAAAAAZc/LNvJlrueZCQ/w395-h529-no/8EFEBC8D-916E-4B5D-B1B8-A6550588FC0D.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;The Intelligent Investor&#34; title=&#34;The Intelligent Investor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investing, according to Graham, consists equally of three elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A company must be analysed thoroughly along with the soundess of its underlying business before buying its stock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One must deliberately protect oneself against serious losses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One should aspire to be adequate return, provided he or she acts with reasonable intelligence&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great tip which he left regarding the purchase of stocks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are shopping for common stocks, choose them the way you would buy groceries, not the way you would buy perfume. - Benjamin Graham&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>