<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Think Different</title>
    <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/categories/personal/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Think Different</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Discomfort Zone</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/discomfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 22:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/discomfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the commonly used terms today, would be &lt;em&gt;comfort zone&lt;/em&gt;. When one is in his or her comfort zone, one feels at ease and safe. Psychologically, one is inclined to stay at such state and not to change to a different state that would affect him or herself, at that point of time. Willpower is required to tell the mind to move out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/cgYPgqX.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Comfort Zone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;complication&#34;&gt;Complication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, when one is at ease and one&amp;rsquo;s mental state wants to remain status quo for the longest possible time, results will be mediocre, in everything done. Then, when the time comes for one to evaluate how one&amp;rsquo;s life has progressed in the past years, reality hits hard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What have I achieved these past years?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Years ago, I had set a goal for myself. How far am I from what I have set out to do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Have I became so complacent that the fire in me is perishing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/wxlyrmP.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reflection&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is always to continue to challenge oneself. When the feeling of comfort sets in, it is time to evaluate the environment one is in and find ways to push ahead. What may have been challenging before, may have been settling now. The pursuit for discomfort and challenges, never ends as that is when one truly discovers about oneself and the capabilities or latent potentials that one has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one life given by God on this Earth, venture to the unknown and explore the depths that life has to offer. Embrace the &lt;strong&gt;discomfort zone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/YFSh0DC.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Discomfort Zone&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Learning</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/the-art-of-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/the-art-of-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;musings-of-learning&#34;&gt;Musings of Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often said that one should never stop learning and the day when one stops learning is when he or she embraces failure or he or she is buried six-feet under. While there are so many things to learn, everyone ought to be selective on what to learn as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/images/learning.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Learning&#34; title=&#34;Learning&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Education institution has always supposed to be, a noble place for everyone to pick up knowledge. Notice the term, &amp;lsquo;supposed&amp;rsquo;. The primary reason why I put the term there is because, what is supposed to be a noble job has become a cash-cow machine or a propaganda tool by those that are in power. I have always been a supporter of capitalism, but when we have a scenario whereby people who did not put into effort are rewarded while people who worked their asses off are not rewarded, regardless of what system or mechanism is being put to sustain such &amp;ldquo;feel-good&amp;rdquo;, it will fail. For example, we have schools here emphasizing that the young padawans should memorize term by term for a moral examination. Probably sometimes most people do not get it but, &lt;strong&gt;memorizing or studying does not equate to doing&lt;/strong&gt;. It is unfortunate to see such noble institution deteriorate to such state, from such noble cause of moving human civilization forward to making people dumber by the day or milking the life out of others just to make money. Heck, as per &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&#34;&gt;Abraham Maslow&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt;, Esteem is one of the base that builds to Self-Actualization! Here we a situation, that people are attempting to limit others&amp;rsquo; access to knowledge to gain Esteem and impeding them from Self-Actualization. So much for &amp;ldquo;Fulfilling The Country&amp;rsquo;s Aspiration&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, with the power of the Internet, the capability of one to access knowledge is has been broken down tremendously. People now can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Google&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; for information which they do not understand and also access to &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/itunes-u/id490217893?mt=8&amp;amp;ls=1&#34;&gt;free online courses of various discipline effort by esteemed higher learning institution around the world&lt;/a&gt;. Nowadays, college dropouts can embrace the power of the Internet by learning web development by themselves and start contributing to the social with useful web application developments and also make some green while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-fussy-about-learning&#34;&gt;Being Fussy About Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our time in this world is limited. We will never know when we will get called by God and leave this world. Thus, it is imperative for us to manage our time from financial aspect to social aspect and that includes learning as well. During high school days, everyone is expected to learning more than 7 subjects and swallow in all the information and just regurgitate them out during examination. So much for learning indeed. Moving on to university, although one has a clearer idea of what he or she wants to do, the same principle still applies (swallow information, regurgitate them during exam), only in a more specialize subject matter. Finally, when it comes to work itself, only a handful of what is learnt is applicable to work. Talk about a waste of time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complication is, most people tend to learn things such as the most recent movies released and also the recent pop songs out in the market rather than focusing on the two skill category above. Seriously? Unless one has vested interest in media, there is no reason to shift most learning capability to the top media items out there in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going forward, it is important for one to know what he or she wants to do in life and how he or she can contribute to the society at large. That will form the basis of how one allocates time to pick up important skillsets that will lead to the goal that is set. It varies among everyone on how long one will take to realize what he or she truly wants but that is the most important step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, lay out all the required skillsets to pick up and get going with the learning. Everyone has the following two big category of skillsets to pick up from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Necessity Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal-Achieving Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Necessity Skills are skills which we cannot run away from. That includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic cooking knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hygiene knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one lacks even one of these skills, he or she has to depend on others and currenly unable to be independent. This is akin to being a toddler and require adults to constant feed him or her. If one cannot manage these Basic Necessity Skills, how will he or she be able to conquer those Goal-Achieving Skills?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goal-Achieving Skills can only be tapped into once one has properly handle his or her Basic Necessity Skills. Here is where one will project where he or she want to be 10 - 20yrs down the road and start working his or her ass off to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, one may aspire to setup a software-as-a-service (SAAS) company. With that, he or she will commence acquiring the knowledge and skills such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyonrails.org/&#34;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/cocoa/conceptual/ProgrammingWithObjectiveC/Introduction/Introduction.html&#34;&gt;Objective-C&lt;/a&gt; in order to build the necessary ecosystem of the SAAS, be it web application or mobile application. Only by having such knowledge then one can manage such company by hiring those others who are good in such field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to identify one&amp;rsquo;s desire, identify the necessary knowledge to achieve the desire and go and learn them and only them in the process of obtaining Goal-Achieving Skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;focused-learning&#34;&gt;Focused Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During learning, one may spend long hours in order to gain the related knowledge. One may also realize that there are people who only spend one or two hours and may potential gain the same amount of information as compared to the earlier personnel before. How does one do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/images/mindmeditation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wonders of the Mind&#34; title=&#34;Wonders of the Mind&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about focused learning; when the mind is atuned to the subject matter, wonderful things will happen. That includes, increased knowledge absorption capability, increased knowledge retention period and increased understandng capability. One may learning items for a almost one full day and barely get anything out of it; that is a pure waste of time and it is a sin. Instead of allocating one full day to pick up knowledge, it is important to understand one&amp;rsquo;s limitation and use that period of learning with focused learning; then use the remaining time for mind-relaxation activities and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like the obvious but one will be surprised on a number of people&amp;rsquo;s attitude when it comes to learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Education is what remains after one has forgotten what one has learned in school.&amp;rdquo; - Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreams and Reality</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/dreams-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/dreams-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-desire&#34;&gt;The Desire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has always been one&amp;rsquo;s desire in order to achieve his or her goals. As per &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow&#39;s_hierarchy_of_needs&#34;&gt;Abraham Maslow&lt;/a&gt;, self-actualisation sits at the top of the hierarchy. The main criteria in order for oneself to achieve self-actualisation would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify one&amp;rsquo;s potentials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live them out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads to desire. Everyone has desires or goals which he or she would like to fulfill during his or her lifetime. Through the the process of identification of goals and achieving them, one finds his or her self-worthiness and what it means to be oneself. Also, he or she would be able to associate with other peers who potentially share the same goals and work together to obtain the same achievement together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only self-actualisation is a self-rewarding stage of life, it also complements the Fourth Need (Esteem) and Third Need (Love and Belonging). Due to this, one is driven towards actualisation discovery regardless how long it may take (from months to years or even a lifetime).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-road-to-dream-realising&#34;&gt;The Road to Dream-Realising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon realising the goal at hand, one would work out plans and ways in order to achieve it. From conceptualisation to execution, many form of paths will be experimented just to find the one that leads to the goal. Not to mention, finding mentors who one can look up to and also reading the journey undertaken by such mentors provide an additional nudge to continue to stay focus on the dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-stumbling-block-of-realism&#34;&gt;The Stumbling Block of Realism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality starts to kick in at the early stage of feedback gathering. This is when one shares with even his or her close friends or family that what he or she set out to achieve. Naturally, they would provide advices which highlight the detrimental effects on going against the norm or the herd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking objectively, perhaps it is just the human mind&amp;rsquo;s tendency to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/03/24/your-money/why-people-remember-negative-events-more-than-positive-ones.html&#34;&gt;remember negative things stronger than positive ones&lt;/a&gt;. Having said that, we may just project what we deemed correct and our experiences which relates to his or her dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to mention, when one breaks down the plan to manageable crumbs, the journey which may seemed quite short, is unexpectedly longer than before. The effort required to continuously pursue the goal and the long term focus is enormous. At times, after spending from hours to days to weeks and months, one would raise this question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it really worth it to pursue this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there are really two forces at play here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The external environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The inner-self&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-continuous-journey&#34;&gt;The Continuous Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all seems bleak, it is good to let intuition to take over the rational mind. One would just shut the rational mind which continuously feed information based on external environment (which may consist of noise and signal) and the inner-self and let the gut-feel come to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wonderful thing about intuition is that it is akin to one&amp;rsquo;s inner-call where lies one&amp;rsquo;s hidden potential. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psychologytoday.com/articles/200212/the-powers-and-perils-intuition&#34;&gt;Let it take over in a controlled manner can yield a powerful personal compass yet let it run wild and the after-effects are not to be trifled with&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/about/&#34;&gt;Scott Adam&lt;/a&gt;, the creator of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt;, has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304626104579121813075903866&#34;&gt;great proposition&lt;/a&gt;. He shared that rather than being goal-oriented, one can opt to be system-oriented. That manner, changes the perception if a goal fails. One can pick up lessons learnt from failures and apply them to the next-big-thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the one who dreamt of a dream which transpired to a desire and goal(s), having to face the stumbling block of reality is part and parcel of the adventure. In the end, if one maintains sufficient focus and listen to one&amp;rsquo;s inner-self, that alone will set one apart from those who dream and work towards it and those who dream and do nothing about it. Such is a wonderful journey which lies ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a reminder to myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Wants and Could Nots</title>
      <link>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/wants-and-could-nots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/post/wants-and-could-nots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gotten the opportunity to talk to so many wonderful individuals (be it friends or families or strangers) throughout my entire life thus far and I notice an interesting trait from most of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I want to be successful in this field but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to spend time in learning it because [insert your own imaginations here].&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It baffles me, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-explained-in-scenario-s-complication-c-question-q-answer-a&#34;&gt;Introduction, explained in Scenario ( S ), Complication ( C ), Question ( Q ) &amp;amp; Answer ( A )&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the benefit of all, SCQA, also known as The Minto Pyramid Principle, is developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barbaraminto.com/&#34;&gt;Barbara Minto&lt;/a&gt;. It is aimed to provide the writer or presenter an engaging introduction to his or her audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the effort to further my background of this post, let me share with you a scenario. We all are aware (or at least I presume we are), that with the concept time value of money, money today would worth more than money in the future. This is because, with the amount of cash which we have today, we can invest it (be it in properties, stocks, businesses, funds etc.) and grow the amount in future. Not to mention, inflation will drive prices up in the future causing rising cost of living. Due to the present opportunity to earn yields and the rise in inflation, thus the value of money will be altered. Many individuals shared with me that they are aware of the need to learn more ample ways to grow money rather than relying on their sole active income (aka employment salary) in order to ensure they can retire fast and rich. However, it is easier said than done, or at least what some may presume it as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bells strikes when it comes to the golden question, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you are aware of it (importance of understanding time value of money), why did not you act on it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Some interesting feedbacks are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t dare to take the risk to do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t commit time for it because I need to work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t have the money to do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want to do it but I don&amp;rsquo;t know who to ask.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the list goes on. So much time have been spent to think of reasons but so little time spent on thinking the solution. Here is the thing, when we move on from young adults to family life, we would even need to devote more time for our beloved future family. That being said, we would even have less time to think about these let alone to act upon it. Then, the reasons continue to stay until one day, our brain reached &amp;ldquo;nirvana&amp;rdquo; thinking, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why am I spending my life doing something which I do not like to do and stay just because of the money? What have I achieved so far as being myself and contribute to the circle of people whom I interact with? When I die, what will I be remembered as?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; That is when the thought of life-crisis happen, be it mid-life or quarter-life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further on, the question I would like to pose out to all, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you serious in reaching your life&amp;rsquo;s goal and not allowing the shackles of finance to restrain you or are you just going to let life pass by you just like that and go with the flow?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I am definitely serious on getting my goals achieved and I would not allow financial conditions to restrain myself from achieving them. When I die, I would want to be remembered as the jerk to most of the people rather than the nobody to all. I am sure you all would want to as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all the inputs which I garnered, I managed to summarize them to three main points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear of uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear of going against the herd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear of failing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-uncertainty&#34;&gt;Fear of Uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our scumbag mind works in an interesting manner. Our brain tends to resist change and always conditions itself to continue to work on things which it is familiar, not things which it is not familiar. Take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&#34;&gt;Abraham Maslow&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt; below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/60/Maslow%27s_Hierarchy_of_Needs.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Maslow&#39;s Hierarchy of Needs&#34; title=&#34;Maslow&#39;s Hierarchy of Needs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Safety Need actually is just above the Physiological Need. That explains why our brain tends to be in a defensive mode whenever there are changes in the external environment of the body. Furthermore, it is programmed in a way to understand that, &lt;strong&gt;the best way of doing things, is continuously doing things which it is familiar with.&lt;/strong&gt; This actually happens due to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classical_conditioning&#34;&gt;Classical or Pavlovian Conditioning&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ivan_Pavlov&#34;&gt;Ivan Pavlov&lt;/a&gt;, he discovered this scenario via pairing of two stimuli in an experiment. He presented the dogs with a ringing bell followed by food. By repetitively doing so, he actually brought together two stimuli (both the dog food and also ringing of the bell). Thus, as the experiment progressed, whenever he rang the bell, the dogs salivated even though there were no food provided to them. The same goes for us; we have been so conditioned to do the ordinary things (e.g. put our money in savings, strive and aim high in employment and live the rat race), until our mind automatically falls back to it whenever we are being presented with different options which may turn out to be better for us in our lives (e.g. invest our money in an investment vehicle, strive for entrepreneurship to improve the needs of people and get out of the rat race).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One good reminder so that we do not fall into the pitfall of our brain&amp;rsquo;s tendency to be defensive and the classical conditioning which has been wired into us; would be, remind ourselves of successful people such as Bill Gates, Warren Buffet, and Richard Branson. They definitely went through times of uncertainty throughout their entire lives and guess what, they do not let uncertainty get the best of them but rather they get the best of it. We can do too, by continuously be open to options and willing to try different things in our lives. At the end of the day, it is always about the journey, not just the end goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-going-against-the-herd&#34;&gt;Fear of Going Against the Herd&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As human beings, we are a social species. We would prefer to have a community to belong to and seek accountability, respect and ultimately, love partner. From &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&#34;&gt;Maslow&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt;, Love and Belonging Need is just above Safety Need. This actually reflects the importance of belongingness for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The twist comes when most people tend to fear uncertainty. Usually, it is in the majority group rather than the minority. For us, if we were to try to act different from the majority, we would be fearful that we will not be accepted by our community, let alone, fostering good companionship with selected individuals from our community. As this cycle goes on, at the end, without realizing, we may potentially end up with the majority; being fearful of uncertainty and bearing a huge opportunity cost. All just because we are fearful that we may not be accepted in our community if we choose to act differently with our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is alright for us to always choose to be different and act as it is. Sometimes, we may ended up being unaccepted by our &lt;em&gt;normal&lt;/em&gt; peers but we may meet with others who are striving to be different as well and take charge of their lives like we are. Here is an interesting quote which can serve as a good reminder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Acquire worldly wisdom and adjust your behaviour accordingly. If your new behaviour gives you a little temporary unpopularity with your peer group then to hell with them.&amp;rdquo; - Charlie Munger, Vice-Chairman of Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-of-failing&#34;&gt;Fear of Failing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/images/failureorsuccess.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Failure or Success&#34; title=&#34;Failure or Success&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do fear failure as much as everyone else do. I am always uncomfortable of failing and would want to be successful in whatever I am doing. I have never been so wrong before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bryanwongbh.github.io/unconventional/images/ihaveneverbeensowrong.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yeah, I have never been so wrong before&#34; title=&#34;Yeah, I have never been so wrong before&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most education systems punish the so-called failures and promote the winners. That is indeed, not very practical to do so especially in real-life which we would need to try things out before knowing that we would fail or succeed. Thanks to such conditioning (yeah, I know right), even for areas such as our career or investing, we dare not take the first step for we fear that we would fail. We fear that if we were to opt for entrepreneurship, we would lose time and also potential promotion if we stick to our normal careers instead. Our peers would potentially surpass us during our absence as they continue to work on their role in their employment. In the investing perspective, we fear that a bear will come and maul our profits and potentially cause us to lose our initial capital as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that &amp;ldquo;Failure is the Mother of Success&amp;rdquo; can be the first step to take, in order to overcome such fear. As cliché as the previous statement may sound, it is actually true. I would testify it from the perspective of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salsa_%28dance%29&#34;&gt;salsa dance&lt;/a&gt;. I dance salsa during my free time, and one of the main responsibility of a salsero is to lead his lady &lt;strong&gt;properly&lt;/strong&gt; on the dance floor. There are occasions (note the term, are) which my lead has to be improved as some ladies told me that they were confused on where I wanted them to do. That sucks, really, and it is a clean hit to the ego. With that, I just swallowed them and continue to note down what I ought to look out for whenever I social dance with ladies. Nowadays, there are times when the ladies commented, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was fun dancing with you! Thanks for being such a great dancer!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; They are edifying indeed but I definitely would note that it is a continuous learning process for myself. This implies the same in the area of investing and also career perspective. It really boils down to how badly we want it. If we really want it badly, we would take failures head on and learn to improve from it and one day, score the goal which we aimed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear is an illusion created by ourselves. It is up to ourselves to go against it head on and make a difference to our lives and the lives around us. Personally, I am always on the wrestle to ensure I do not give in to my fears and continue to set my eyes upon my dreams. With that, let me share a great quote with you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The future belongs to those who believe in the beauty of their dream&amp;rdquo; - Eleanor Roosevelt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>